

Software Engineer

(±351) 93 502 44 10 andygoncalves.com in andygoncalves seekandystroy



General

Traits An enthusiastic and straightforward team player, I love to learn and hear about different points of view. Very communicative, love getting feedback and improving.

Interests Distributed systems and cloud computing. Software development and engineering in general.

Experience Architecture and implementation of the backend of cloud applications. Implementation of all the stack levels of web applications. Some experience in functional analysis and design of web and mobile applications. Master thesis in cloud computing.

Life Biker, keyboard enthusiast, and former competing martial artist.

Professional Experience

2016-now Talkdesk, (2 year, 10 months), Software Engineer, Cloud-based call center solution. Designing and developing the new core systems of the product, responsible for routing and calls and other interactions.

Maintaining the legacy call routing system.

2013–2016 Safira/KPMG, (2 years, 5 months), Software Developer, IT for financial services. Full stack development of web applications, mobile web applications, and middlewares, for banks and insurance companies, using IBM technologies.

Education

2011–2013 Masters in Computer Science Engineering, Nova University, Lisbon, 17/20. 2 years MSc (Eng), focus on distributed systems. Thesis in cloud storage systems, with a grade of 18/20.

2012 Teaching assistant, Nova University, Lisbon, Introduction to Computers and Programming.

2008–2011 Diploma in Computer Science Engineering, Nova University, Lisbon, 15/20. 3 years BSc (Eng).

Technical Skills

General OO/functional programming, TDD, SOA and Microservices, event-driven architectures

Languages Ruby, Elixir, Java (main ones)

Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, C, C++, Matlab, Python, PHP, Prolog

DBs MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

Tools Git, SVN, Unix/Linux usage, LATEX

Misc. Docker, Twilio, Heroku, IBM BPM, IIB/WMB